<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-04-28T16:48:33+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Welcome to Bioinformatics Hub of Kenya Intiative</title><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title type="html">Bioinformatics Hub of Kenya Intiative!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2020/04/27/welcome-to-jekyll.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bioinformatics Hub of Kenya Intiative!" /><published>2020-04-27T16:47:06+03:00</published><updated>2020-04-27T16:47:06+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2020/04/27/welcome-to-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2020/04/27/welcome-to-jekyll.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-bhki&quot;&gt;About BHKi&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bioinformatics is a multidisciplinary field, and requires expertise in computer technology, biology, statistics and mathematics. Training in bioinformatics does not simply require formal training in each of these disciplines, but also the integration of this knowledge and coherent application thereof to problems in biology. Research in modern biology, similarly, requires cross application of knowledge in an integrated fashion. The multidisciplinary nature of bioinformatics involves integration of various disciplines such as computer science, biology, statistics and mathematics.Therefore, to address the requirement for multidisciplinary training in bioinformatics, the establishment of new training programs that combine the required constituent fields are needed. To nurture and promote bioinformatics research will require an organizational entity that can facilitate the integration of these disciplines, promote the integration of skills and allow productive intellectual exchange and discussion in addressing bioinformatics questions. In other words, an entity that can facilitate the formation of a critical mass in bioinformatics research expertise.The Bioinformatics Hub of Kenya represents such an entity that can develop and manage training in bioinformatics and computational biology and a space in which research in bioinformatics is practiced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;our-mission&quot;&gt;Our Mission&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To bridge the gap between well established and aspiring bioinformaticians through peer training and mentorship so as to enhance collaborations to foster quality scientific research and innovations and promote the sharing of data, skills and codes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;our-vision&quot;&gt;Our Vision&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be a vivacious, well-coordinated and enthusiastic hub that will develop bioinformatics and skills set through creating awareness, collaborations and capacity development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;key-activities&quot;&gt;Key activities&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Training&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Networking&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Peer learning&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Outreach events&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">About BHKi</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Being a member of Bioinformatics Hub of Kenya Intiative!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2020/04/27/Membership.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Being a member of Bioinformatics Hub of Kenya Intiative!" /><published>2020-04-27T16:47:06+03:00</published><updated>2020-04-27T16:47:06+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2020/04/27/Membership</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2020/04/27/Membership.html"></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry></feed>